International Workers Order (IWO) Records 5276
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Bombardier (Lodge 466) (Box 46, Folder 7)
- Budget for Survival (Box 46, Folder 8)
- The Builder (Lodge 253) (Box 46, Folder 9)
- Characteristics of Young Gifted Children (Box 46, Folder 10)
- Child-Welfare Legislation (Box 46, Folder 11)
- Children Engaged in Newspaper and Magazine Selling and Delivering (Box 46, Folder 12)
- Children In the Land of Socialism (Box 46, Folder 13)
- Children's Progress (Box 46, Folder 14)
- Contemporary Jewish Record (Box 46, Folder 15)
- A Crime Against Jewish Unity (Box 46, Folder 16)
- The Democratic Government and Army of Free Greece (Box 46, Folder 17)
- Divide and Conquer (Box 46, Folder 18)
- Escape To Life (Box 46, Folder 19)
- Facts About Child Health (Box 46, Folder 20)
- Facts About the Jewish National Fund (Box 46, Folder 21)
- Five Things You Can Do Today To Help Win the Peace (Box 46, Folder 22)
- Foreign War Relief (Box 46, Folder 23)
- Fortissimi sunt Belgae (Box 46, Folder 24)
- Fraternalists (Lodge 817) (Box 46, Folder 25)
- Fraternally Yours (Lodge 795) (Box 46, Folder 26)
- Good Posture In the Little Child (Box 46, Folder 27)
- Greater Security In the JPFO (Box 46, Folder 28)
- The Growth of Hebrew Culture in America (Box 46, Folder 29)
- Haganah (Box 46, Folder 30)
- Haganah Speaks To the U.N. (Box 46, Folder 31)
- Help! Rehabilitate the Jewish People (Box 46, Folder 32)
- HIAS (Box 46, Folder 33)
- Higher and H-I-R-E Education (Box 46, Folder 34)
- The Home Front (Box 46, Folder 35)
- Insurance in Wartime (Box 46, Folder 36)
- The Jewish Fraternalists (Box 46, Folder 37)
- Jewish Life (Box 46, Folder 38)
- The Jewish People Will Live On (Box 46, Folder 39)
- Jews In American Democratic Movements (Box 46, Folder 40)
- Leningrad (Box 46, Folder 41)
- A Letter From Madame Chiang Kai-Shek... (Box 46, Folder 42)
- Letter To a Zionist Friend (Box 46, Folder 43)
- Lodge Life (Lodge 517) (Box 46, Folder 44)
- Lodge Log (Local 585) (Box 46, Folder 45)
- Masaryk Charts Jewish Future (Box 46, Folder 46)
- Model Meeting (Lodge 600) (Box 46, Folder 47)
- Never To Forget (The Battle of the Warsaw Ghetto) (Box 46, Folder 48)
- News From Belgium (Box 46, Folder 49)
- Number 871433 Sends You Thanks (Box 46, Folder 50)
- Observations of Successful Business Executives (Box 46, Folder 51)
- Organized Labor and the Fascist Danger (Box 46, Folder 52)
- Oust Bilbo (Box 46, Folder 53)
- The Patriot (Haym Salomon Lodge) (Box 46, Folder 54)
- Plans For Jewish Schools (Box 46, Folder 55)
- Purim (Box 46, Folder 56)
- Purim Time Is Here (Box 46, Folder 57)
- Questions and Answers About Progressive Jewish Childrens Schools (Box 46, Folder 58)
- Remember the Dead - Rescue the Living (Box 46, Folder 59)
- The Road Back (Box 46, Folder 60)
- The Schools and Civilian Defense (Box 46, Folder 61)
- School For Teachers and Higher Jewish Education (Box 46, Folder 62)
- Security Equality Fraternalism (Lodge 471) (Box 46, Folder 63)
- So Your Son Wants To Be a Doctor (Box 46, Folder 64)
- Soldiers' Village (Box 46, Folder 65)
- Solemn Assembly of Sorrow and Protest (Box 46, Folder 66)
- Sosua-Refugee Haven in the Caribbean (Box 46, Folder 67)
- Speaking As American Jews and Zionists (Box 46, Folder 68)
- Survey Midmonthly (Box 46, Folder 69)
- Shushan Review (Box 46, Folder 70)
- Tale of a City (Box 46, Folder 71)
- Technology In Palestine (Box 46, Folder 72)
- Three Gifts and Other Stories by Peretz (Box 46, Folder 73)
- Together As Jews - As Americans (Box 46, Folder 74)
- Trade Unions in Greece (Box 46, Folder 75)
- The Tuscon Fraternalists (Lodge 453) (Box 46, Folder 76)
- Unity of the Jews For Victory (Box 46, Folder 77)
- Unity Won the War - Unity Won't Win the Peace (Box 46, Folder 78)
- Victory For Freedom (Box 46, Folder 79)
- We Suffer In A Thousand Ways (Box 46, Folder 80)
- What Happens To Your $4 Hadassah Dues? (Box 46, Folder 81)
- Women of the USA and the USSR (Box 46, Folder 82)
- Work Camps For College Students (Box 46, Folder 83)
- You Gave Them This Courage (Box 46, Folder 84)
- Yugntvort (Box 46, Folder 85)
- Abraham Goldfoden (Box 47, Folder 1)
- Almanac of JPFO (Box 47, Folder 2)
- Anti-Semitism in U.S. (Box 47, Folder 3)
- Bulletin (Box 47, Folder 4)
- Capitalism, Socialism and Communism (Box 47, Folder 5)
- Commemorating Warsaw Ghetto Uprising (Box 47, Folder 6)
- Communism For What and For Whom (Box 47, Folder 7)
- Communist Manifesto (Box 47, Folder 8)
- Culture and Nation (Box 47, Folder 9)
- Culture, Work, Fraternalism in Inner Life (Box 47, Folder 10)
- David Bergelson (Box 47, Folder 11)
- David Edelshot (Box 47, Folder 12)
- Der Hammer (Box 47, Folder 13)
- Disqualified Not 1947 (Box 47, Folder 14)
- Ethics and Purpose of the IWO (Box 47, Folder 15)
- For Homeland In Battle (Box 47, Folder 16)
- For the Security and Health of the People (Box 47, Folder 17)
- For Soviet Russia (Box 47, Folder 18)
- For Unity and For a Victory (Box 47, Folder 19)
- Germany - Destruction (Box 47, Folder 20)
- Give Back the World, Bourgeois and Other Songs (Box 47, Folder 21)
- The Great Conspiracy (Box 47, Folder 22)
- Guidebook For Builders of the Order (Box 47, Folder 23)
- Help! Rehabilitate the Jewish People (Box 47, Folder 24)
- Holidays (Box 47, Folder 25)
- In Service To the People (Box 47, Folder 26)
- The IWO In Jewish Life (Box 47, Folder 27)
- IWW Songbook (Box 68, Folder 1)
- Jane Adams (Box 68, Folder 2)
- Jews In the Soviet Union (Box 68, Folder 3)
- Jewish Culture Society In Poland, Record of National Convention (Box 68, Folder 4)
- Jewish Folk Songs (Box 68, Folder 5)
- Jewish Literature in America (Box 68, Folder 6)
- Jewish People In American Freedom (Labor) Organization (Box 68, Folder 7)
- Jewish Unity Towards Victory (Box 68, Folder 8)
- Kinder Journal (Box 68, Folder 9)
- Marxism Study Course (Box 68, Folder 10)
- The Molly Maguires (Box 68, Folder 11)
- Mother Bloor (Box 68, Folder 12)
- My Book Reader (Box 68, Folder 13)
- Nation and Culture (Box 47.1, Folder 1)
- NAI Teatur (Box 47.1, Folder 2)
- Negro Poetry in America, 1936 (Box 47.1, Folder 3)
  Removed from collection and now housed in Kheel Center Rare Books
- On the Hill (Box 47.1, Folder 4)
- Order Bulletin (Box 47.1, Folder 5)
- Our Debt To the Soviet Union (Box 47.1, Folder 6)
- Our Heroes and Leaders: Who Was Steve Kataves? (Box 47.1, Folder 7)
- Peretz, Y. L. (Box 47.1, Folder 8)
- Proletariat Educator (Box 47.1, Folder 9)
- Questions and Answers About the Jewish Progressive Schools (Box 47.1, Folder 10)
- Response To Sholom Asch and H. Levik (Box 47.1, Folder 11)
- Response To David Pinsk (Box 47.1, Folder 12)
- Morris Pozenfeld (Songs and Poetry) (Box 47.1, Folder 13)
- School Bulletin (Box 47.1, Folder 14)
- Seforim, Mendele Mocher (Box 47.1, Folder 15)
- Shalom Aleichem (Box 47.1, Folder 16)
- The Solving of the Jewish Question in Soviet Russia (Box 47.1, Folder 17)
- Soviet Union Build Socialism (Box 47.1, Folder 18)
- The Spark (Box 47.1, Folder 19)
- Ten Years of Fraternalism (Box 47.1, Folder 20)
- Under the Silk Curtains of the American Jewish Congress (Box 47.1, Folder 21)
- Unzer Wort (Box 47.1, Folder 22)
- Vintchusky, Morris (Box 47.1, Folder 23)
- The Voice of the Progressive Cloak Finishers (Box 47.1, Folder 24)
- The War and the Working Class (Box 47.1, Folder 25)
- The War Danger (Box 47.1, Folder 26)
- Why You Must Join the IWO (Box 47.1, Folder 27)
- The Woman at Home, Factory and In Society (Box 47.1, Folder 28)
- Worker-School Studybook (Box 47.1, Folder 29)
- Yearly School Almanac (Box 47.1, Folder 30)
- Your Child (Box 47.1, Folder 31)
- Yungvarg (Box 47.1, Folder 32)
- Aptheker, Herbert. The Meaning of Negro History. (Box 48, Folder 1)
  8 p.
- Bardi, Gino. Are We Aryans?, 1939 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  39 p.
- Bedacht, Max. Labor Fraternalism - the Fraternal Principles and Program of the I.W.O., 1941 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  31 p.
- Bedacht, Max. The Organizer and His Problems (Box 48, Folder 4)
  18 p.
- Bedacht, Max. Unity of the Fraternal Movement., 1936 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  24 p
- Benjamin, Herbert. For an Offensive on the Second European Front., 1942 (Box 48, Folder 6)
- Blake, Ben, ed. 12 Plays for Boys and Girls., 1935 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  79 p.
- International Workers Order (IWO). Add IWO Protection to Your Union Protection. (Box 48, Folder 8)
  12:00 PM
- IWO. Air Raids, Blackouts, First Aid., 1942 (Box 48, Folder 9)
- IWO. The Best Insurance Protection For Your Family., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  47 p.
- IWO. Civilian and National Defense Exposition., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  3 p.
- IWO. The Film Division of the IWO Presents., 1946 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  2p.
- IWO. Food For Freedom Bulletin., 1946 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  July, 1946. 4 p.
- IWO. Five Years of the International Workers Order., 1935 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  1935 123 p
- IWO. Fraternal Outlook. ,scattered issues., 1939-1950 (Box 48, Folder 15)
- IWO. How to Organize an IWO Lodge - a Point by Point Outline (Box 48, Folder 16)
  5:00 PM
- IWO. The IWO - History and Role in Political Life of Our Country. (Box 48, Folder 17)
  (Includes instructor's outline, 8 p.)
- IWO. IWO On Parade - 4th Convention, Pittsburgh, PA. (Box 48, Folder 18)
  22 p.
- IWO. An Indictment - The People vs. Attorney General Tom Clark Before the Court of Public Opinion. (Box 48, Folder 19)
  6p.
- IWO. IWO Junior Guide., 1940 (Box 48, Folder 20)
  May, 8 p.
- IWO. The Lodge Program - II. (Box 48, Folder 21)
  6 p.
- IWO. The Lodge Program - III. (Box 48, Folder 22)
  13 p.
- IWO. Membership Book. (Box 48, Folder 23)
  12p.
- IWO. News Bulletin., 1951 (Box 48, Folder 24)
  April, 8 p.
- IWO. News From the International Workers Order., scattered issues., 1942-1950 (Box 48, Folder 25)
- IWO. Notes and Materials For Speakers On Attorney Genera Clark's Report To The Loyalty Board. (Box 48, Folder 26)
  15p.
- IWO. Our Plan For Plenty. (Box 48, Folder 27)
  32 p.
- IWO. Our Plan For Plenty. (Box 48, Folder 28)
  3p.
- IWO. Our Spring Offensive ... Report To the National Women's Committee., 1942 (Box 48, Folder 29)
  10p.
- IWO. An Outline of Parliamentary procedure and the Conduct of a Lodge Meeting. (Box 48, Folder 30)
- IWO. Promoting Security - Facts About the Role and Purpose of the IWO., 1940 (Box 48, Folder 31)
- IWO. Rate Schedule., 1945 (Box 48, Folder 32)
- IWO. Speaker's Outline On ... the IWO and Social Security. (Box 48, Folder 33)
  5p.
- IWO. Special Bulletin., 1945 (Box 48, Folder 34)
  July, 4p.
- IWO. Season's Greetings from International Workers Order., 1943 (Box 48, Folder 35)
  1p.
- IWO. Three Years -. A Review of the IWO Between the 6th and 7th Convention.. 89 p., 1944-1947 (Box 48, Folder 36)
  89p.
- IWO. To Every Member of the IWO - A Message From Our President - William Weiner., 1941 (Box 48, Folder 37)
  7 p.
- IWO. Workers School, Textbook For the Third Year., 1934 (Box 48, Folder 38)
  113 p.
- IWO. City Central Committee. Education Department. War Activities Guide for IWO Community Councils. (Box 48, Folder 39)
- IWO. Cultural Council. Cultural Counsel., 1943 (Box 48, Folder 40)
  December, (Volume 1, Number 1).
- IWO. Film Division. Films For Victory. 35 p., 1945 (Box 48, Folder 41)
  35 p.
- IWO. Front Line Fighters Fund. This Is Your Enemy - A Documentary of Nazi Atrocities Against Citizens and Soldiers of Our Soviet Ally., 1942 (Box 48, Folder 42)
  45 p
- IWO. General Executive Board. Manual For Lodge Officers of the International Workers Order., 1939 (Box 48, Folder 43)
  72 p.
- IWO. General Office. Discussion Guide - "The People Have Never Abandoned F.D.R.'s Policies"., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 44)
  16 p.
- IWO. General Office Staff. The Paper., 1948 (Box 48, Folder 45)
  January- Number 4. 10 p.
- IWO. Medical Department. At Your Service 365 Days a Year. (Box 48, Folder 46)
  2 p.
- IWO. National Army Welfare Committee. Dear Son Max (Box 48, Folder 47)
  4p.
- IWO. National Committee of Young Fraternalists. Fraternalism in Action - Army Welfare Campaign of the IWO., 1941 (Box 48, Folder 48)
- IWO. National Department For Children's Activities. IWO National Junior Leadership School., 1948 (Box 48, Folder 49)
- IWO. National Department For Children's Activities. Let's Have a Party - Parties For IWO Juniors. (Box 48, Folder 50)
  11 p.
- IWO. National Education Department. Education For Victory -Series 1., 1942 (Box 68, Folder 14)
  8p.
- IWO. National Education Department. Education For Victory Series 2., 1942 (Box 68, Folder 15)
- IWO. National Education Department. The Hungarian People Their Traditions and Contributions. (Box 68, Folder 16)
- IWO. National Education Department. Labor and the IWO A Handbook., 1937-1941 (Box 68, Folder 17)
- IWO. National Education Department. My Country's Peace Policy Course., 1940 (Box 68, Folder 18)
  9p.
- IWO. National Education Department. Our Civic Duty Keep America Out of War., 1939 (Box 68, Folder 19)
- IWO. National Education Department. Social Games For Lodges (Tenth Anniversary Publication)., 1939 (Box 68, Folder 20)
  37p.
- I.W.O. National Education Dept. "The Hungarian People" (Box 68, Folder 21)
- I.W.O. National Education Dept. "Labor and the I.W.O." (Box 68, Folder 22)
- I.W.O. National Education Dept. "My Country's Peace Policy" (Box 68, Folder 23)
- I.W.O. National Education Dept. "Our Civic Duty" (Box 68, Folder 24)
- I.W.O. National Education Dept. "Social Games for Lodges" (Box 68, Folder 25)
- IWO. National Executive Committee. Manual of the IWO., 1936 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  64p.
- IWO. National Executive Committee. A New Worker's Stronghold What Is the IWO and Why Every Worker Should Join It., 1930 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  16p.
- IWO. National Training School. Workers Fraternalism As a Force In the Community., 1938 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  13p.
- IWO. National Youth Committee. Parliamentary Procedure., 1937 (Box 49, Folder 4)
- IWO. New York Council. Eighteenth Annual Almanac., 1930-1948 (Box 49, Folder 5)
- IWO. New York District. Call To a Cultural Conference. (Box 49, Folder 6)
- IWO. Ukrainian American Fraternal Union. First Ukrainian National Folk Festival., 1948 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  44 p.
- IWO. Young Fraternalists. Those Who Serve - Deserve., 1941 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  1 p.
- IWO. Youth Section. The New Order. (Box 49, Folder 9)
  Volume 1, Number 1-3 and 7 (Title change from Barricade.)
- Marcantonio, Vito. Security With FDR., 1944 (Box 49, Folder 10)
- Schaeffer, Jacob, comp. "Mit Gezang Tzum Kamf" - Songs For Voice and Piano. 74, 1932 (Box 49, Folder 11)
- Starobin, Joseph. Never Again!, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 12)
- Starobin, Joseph. The San Francisco World Security Conference (Box 49, Folder 13)
- Vail, Sol. This Is Treason., 1943 (Box 49, Folder 14)
  28 p.
- Wallace, Henry. Century of the Common Man., 1943 (Box 49, Folder 15)
  46 p.
- Miscellaneous manuscripts. (Box 49, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous manuscripts. (Box 49, Folder 17)
- Amerika Hrvatski Gladnick (American Croatian Herald), 1955 (Box 49, Folder 18)
  Croatian. Newspaper, October 12, 1955.
- Untranslated Hungarian IWO publications (Box 49, Folder 19)
  Hungarian. 10 publications.
- Siamo Ariani (We are Aryans) (Box 49, Folder 20)
  Italian
- Untranslated Polish IWO publications (Box 49, Folder 21)
  Polish and English. "For Your and Our Freedom" two copies. "For Unity and Action" one copy.
- Untranslated Russian IWO publications (Box 49, Folder 22)
  Russian and English. 14 publications.
- Twenty Years: Russian Section 1920-1940 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  Russian. Three copies.
- Thirty Years AROV 1920-1950 (untranslated) (Box 49, Folder 24)
  Russian. Two soft-cover copies. American-Russian Fraternal Society.
- Thirty Years AROV 1920-1950 (untranslated) (Box 49, Folder 25)
  Russian. One hardcover copy. American-Russian Fraternal Society.
- Untranslated Ukrainian IWO publications (Box 49, Folder 26)
  Ukrainian. Three publications.
- Kinderland, 1921-1930 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  Yiddish
- Derwabung, 1939 (Box 50, Folder 2)
- "Our Way" and others bound together, 1925-1933 (Box 50, Folder 3)
- Publications of the Workman's Circle School, 1927-1930 (Box 50, Folder 4)
- The Spark, 1930-1932 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  Yiddish. v.1:no.1 (1930:Sept.) - v.3:no.6 (1932:Dec.)
- Du Sable Community Center, Inc. - Founder's Fund (Box 51, Folder 1)
- IWO Pins (Box 51, Folder 2)
- American Soldiers in New Guinea (Box 51, Folder 3)
- Americans for Haganah (Box 51, Folder 4)
- Children (Box 51, Folder 5)
- Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order (Box 51, Folder 6)
- Pennsylvania (Box 51, Folder 7)
- Portraits, Unidentified (Box 51, Folder 8)
- Recreation (Box 51, Folder 9)
- Slovack Workers Society (Box 51, Folder 10)
- Slovack Workers Society (Box 51, Folder 11)
- Trunikoff, Chaim Lazar (Box 51, Folder 12)
- Soviet Union (Jewish) (Box 51, Folder 13)
- Unidentified (Box 51, Folder 14)
- Yiddish (Box 51, Folder 15)
- Holiday Postcards (Box 51, Folder 16)
- Mrs. America Posters (Box 51, Folder 17)
- Metal Stamp "United Jewish Appeal" (Box 51, Folder 18)
- "368.4 Charts re: Social Security Law" (Box 51, Folder 19)
- Money Campaign for Ten Tanks for USSR (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Non-Affiliated Yiddish Schools (Box 52, Folder 2)
- Secular Yiddish Schools (Box 52, Folder 3)
- Schools, Education (Box 52, Folder 4)
- Issue of Modern Culture (Box 52, Folder 5)
- Dr. Chiam Zhitlorski (Box 52, Folder 6)
- Yiddish Literature (Box 52, Folder 7)
- Yiddish Schools (Box 52, Folder 8)
- Clippings concerning Education (Box 52, Folder 9)
- Current (1993) Jewish Affairs (News Clippings) (Box 52, Folder 10)
- Notes on Culture (Against 20th Century) (Box 52, Folder 11)
- News Clippings about Jews in America (Box 52, Folder 12)
- Tehran Conference (Box 52, Folder 13)
- Jewish War Hero Stories (Box 52, Folder 14)
- IWO Related News Clippings (Box 52, Folder 15)
- War - related material (Box 52, Folder 16)
- Children in wartime (Box 52, Folder 17)
- Education related (Box 52, Folder 18)
- News Clippings about America (Box 52, Folder 19)
- Reports from Morning Freiheit (Phila., Workmen's Circle, School, Conference) (Box 52, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 18)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 20)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 21)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 22)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 24)
- Correspondence, news clippings, notes, and other materials (Box 53, Folder 25)
- Miscellany-files of Executive Secretary R. Saltzman (Box 53, Folder 1)
- Address of R. Saltzman on the30th anniversary of Morgan Freiheit, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  Yiddish. Carnegie Hall, April 26, 1952
- Notes on hearing in Court of Appeals, 1953 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  Yiddish. February 25, 1953; Yiddish version (translation?) of Petition for Certiorari, IWO v. Bollinger, 4/23/1953, etc.
- Correspondence to R. Saltzman and re: R. Saltzman Jubilee Committee, 1941 (Box 53, Folder 4)
- NB Letter from H. Leivick and J. Opatashu to [Haim] Sloves, 1937 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  Yiddish. August 4, 1937 re: preparations for Jewish Culture Congress; Sloves reply; correspondence and other documents re: establishment of Jewish Peoples' Home in Warsaw, 1952
- Various notes for reports, etc. [R. Saltzman] (Box 53, Folder 6)
- R. Saltzman correspondence with H. Sloves of World Jewish Culture Congress, 1938 (Box 53, Folder 7)
- R. Saltzman addresses on various occasions (Box 53, Folder 8)
  Yiddish. mid-1950s
- R. Saltzman, correspondence (Box 53, Folder 9)
  Yiddish. Including re: Polish relief; letter to H. Smolar, etc.
- R. Saltzman, correspondence and addresses (Box 53, Folder 10)
  Yiddish. printed letter from Soviet ambassador; "My Meeting with Albert Einstein"
- R. Saltzman reports (Box 53, Folder 11)
  Yiddish. re: "the insurance occupiers" and about proposed Jewish People's Home in Ridgefield, CT
- R. Saltzman correspondence with Europe (Box 53, Folder 12)
  Yiddish. re: orphanages; etc.; outline of dates in history of JPFO
- Protocols of National Board meeting, 1947-1948 (Box 53, Folder 13)
- Protocols of National Board meeting, 1946 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  Yiddish. Summary of Saltzman testimony in court; other correspondence and clippings
- R. Saltzman-various addresses and reports (Box 53, Folder 15)
- R. Saltzman-clippings and miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 16)
- R. Saltzman miscellaneous; report from Wroclaw (Box 53, Folder 17)
- R. Saltzman correspondence with Poland (Box 53, Folder 18)
  Yiddish. re: relief, e.g. telegram asking for 100 grams streptomycin
- R. Saltzman miscellaneous; reports about trip to Europe (Box 53, Folder 19)
- Clippings and R. Saltzman report (Box 53, Folder 20)
- Yiddish translation of Das Kapital, drafts and marked galleys (Box 53, Folder 21)
- Clippings (Box 53, Folder 22)
- Clippings (Box 53, Folder 23)
- R. Saltzman report to National Board meeting, 1948 (Box 53, Folder 24)
- R. Saltzman notebook (Box 53, Folder 25)
- Jewish Life: A Progressive Monthly (Box 53.1, Folder 1)
- Warsaw Accuses (Box 53.1, Folder 2)
- Schodza hlavneho odboru SRS-IWO odbyvana [ledger], Black and white photograph (Box 54A, Folder 1)
- Zapisnica hl. Odborie: Slov. Rob., Text (Box 54B, Folder 1)
- Jewish Delegation Fourth National Convention: IWO -- Pittsburgh April 23-30, 1938, Text (Box 55, Folder 1)